ndp.ca 2019-11-04

# Privacy Policy « Canada's NDP

**Our Commitment to Respecting and Protecting Your Privacy**

Canada’s NDP is committed to respecting and protecting your privacy, including your personal information. Our policy is in strict compliance with Canadian privacy principles, as well as our obligations under the _Canada Elections Act_. We are committed to ensuring the confidentiality and security of your personal information.

This page summarizes our privacy policy and information practices for the NDP including this website ndp.ca. It is intended to provide information to help you make informed decisions when choosing to communicate with and interact with us.

 **Collecting Personal Information**

“Personal information” is information about an identifiable individual. It includes information such as your name, addresses, email address, telephone number, financial and demographic information.

Elections Canada provides all registered political parties with the List of Electors, which includes names and addresses. We also collect information from publicly available data sources.

We collect the personal information that you choose to provide to us when you become a donor, a member, when you voluntarily subscribe to our communications, when you register for an event or sign a petition either in person or online, when you complete any of the forms on NDP.ca and through voter contact activities, such as door-to-door canvassing and phone calls.

If you submit your email address and/or personal information through NDP.ca, you consent to being added to our email and/or contact list and to receive future communications from us.

 **Using Personal Information**

We use your personal information to communicate with you about the NDP, to provide you with news and information about the NDP and our activities, and to contact you about your past and future donations and membership.

As we are a federal party, we may share your information internally within our national organization, including with NDP riding associations and provincial sections.

We use your financial information to process your donations. We are also required by the _Canada Elections Act_ to provide Elections Canada with information related to the donations you make to us.

 **Protecting Your Personal Information**

Your privacy is very important to us. We protect your personal information by employing rigorous security systems and strict access controls in order to safeguard your personal information from unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or misuse. All users of our systems must agree to terms of use that include language on protecting your privacy before being authorized to use our systems.

We may engage third parties to provide us with services from time-to-time, such as hosting servers and websites, processing online donations, or providing technical or communications services. When information is shared with third parties for these purposes, we ensure that your personal information is rigorously protected by including privacy safeguards in all our contracts, including stringent confidentiality and non-disclosure provisions.

Under no circumstances does the NDP sell your personal information to any third parties.

In the event of a privacy breach, the NDP is committed to documenting the circumstances that led to the breach, the personal identifying information that might have been compromised and immediately and proactively informing affected individuals.

The NDP provides its employees with training on the Party’s privacy policy, including its collection and use of personal information, as well as, how to securely maintain this information.

 **Privacy officer**

In an effort to ensure that your privacy is protected and that the NDP is accountable to you, the party has designated a privacy officer, who is responsible for ensuring that your privacy and this policy is being respected. The privacy officer is also accountable for ensuring that any recipients of your personal information safeguard the security and integrity of your information.

 **Visiting NDP.ca**

When visiting NDP.ca, your privacy is respected and protected.

Any information collected while you are visiting NDP.ca, such as server log data, is managed in accordance with this privacy policy and is protected by applicable law. Server logs include statistical information, such as visitors' IP addresses, time and duration of visits, and pages visited. These statistics may be used to improve your experience on NDP.ca.

In addition, non-personal information may be collected through the use of cookies. Cookies are small text files maintained by your browser in order to remember user settings as you navigate the site. NDP.ca uses cookies, for example, to remind your browser whether you chose to view our website in English or in French. You can also adjust your browser’s settings to refuse cookies, or to accept them on a case-by-case basis.

 **Linking to External Sites**

Other sites to which we provide links may be governed by different policies. The NDP does not assume responsibility for the information practices of these other sites, and we strongly encourage all our visitors to review the privacy policies and statements of all externally-linked sites.

 **Updating your Personal Information**

We aim to keep your information accurate and up-to-date. To update or correct the personal information you provide to us, please contact us at [contact@ndp.ca](mailto:info@ndp.ca).

 **Contacting Us**

Questions or concerns about our privacy policy or the information we collect may be directed to our Privacy Officer, Jesse Calvert at [privacy@ndp.ca](mailto:CanadasNDP-LeNPDduCanada@ndp.ca).

You can also contact us by phone at 613-236-3613 or by postal mail at the address below:

New Democratic Party of Canada  
Suite 300 - 279 Laurier Avenue West  
Ottawa, Ontario K1P 5J9

If you no longer wish to be contacted by us or wish to be placed on our internal Do-Not-Call list, please let us know by emailing [dnc@ndp.ca](mailto:dnc@ndp.ca). You may also unsubscribe from our communications by using the unsubscribe mechanisms contained in all of our electronic messages.
